<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[GPPainHelp test]]></title><description><![CDATA[Web page demonstrating Gatsby+Forestry can do as a PWA for GPPainHelp]]></description><link>http://www.gppainhelp.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 12:49:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Patient FAQs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Q1: If I start taking morphine now, doesn’t that mean there’ll be nothing to control my pain at the end? A: No, it’s important to get your…]]></description><link>http://www.gppainhelp.com/my-second-post/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gppainhelp.com/my-second-post/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1: If I start taking morphine now, doesn’t that mean there’ll be nothing to control my pain at the end?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: No, it’s important to get your pain controlled so your quality of life is improved. The morphine dose can be increased if necessary, and there are many other similar drugs that can be tried if morphine no longer controls your pain adequately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q2: I’ve had morphine before and it made me sick; doesn’t that mean I’m allergic to it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: No, it’s common for people to experience nausea and vomiting when first taking drugs such as morphine. You can be given a small dose of a medication to help control that (e.g. metoclopramide 10mg oral tds) and it should settle within a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q3: I don’t want to take morphine in case I get addicted to it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: Research has confirmed what most doctors and nurses know already – that use of strong medications such as morphine for pain control does not lead to addiction (psychological dependence).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formulations see PBS A-Z Medicine Listing (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbs.gov.au/browse/medicine-listing&quot;&gt;www.pbs.gov.au/browse/medicine-listing&lt;/a&gt;)*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q4: My pain isn’t properly controlled by my medication; should I try another one?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;: You should speak with your GP or specialist palliative care team member. You may have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gppainhelp.com/Content_Hub_Incident_Pain.html&quot;&gt;incident pain&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gppainhelp.com/Breakthrough_Pain.html&quot;&gt;breakthrough pain&lt;/a&gt;, which should be able to be controlled.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introduction and Disclaimer]]></title><description><![CDATA[Introduction Welcome to the GP Pain Help App, to help GPs manage cancer pain in their patients. General principles Opioids are the only…]]></description><link>http://www.gppainhelp.com/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gppainhelp.com/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the GP Pain Help App, to help GPs manage cancer pain in their patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opioids are the only pharmacological class of drug with the ability to control severe pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use oral route first line where possible. test&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dose regularly with controlled-release (CR) preparations, with as required (prn) immediate-release (IR) doses (1/6 daily dose) to assess analgesic requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titrate dose against effect and toxicity – consider switching to another class of opioid if toxicity becomes dose-limiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information within this app is presented by the Centre for Palliative Care Research and Education (CPCRE) for the purpose of disseminating health information free of charge and for the benefit of the healthcare professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While CPCRE has exercised due care in ensuring the accuracy of the material herein, the information provided should be treated as a guide only to appropriate practice, to be followed subject to the clinician’s judgment and the patient’s preference in each individual case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CPCRE does not accept any liability for any injury, loss or damage incurred by use of or reliance on the information contained herein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CPCRE acknowledges the assistance of Professor Janet Hardy and Dr Phillip Good in development of this pain aid for GPs.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>